[
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 38,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 3,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Druid",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A wandering druid.",
            "job": "I seek justice.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "JUST",
            "keyword2": "SHRI",
            "answer1": "Learn at the shrine!",
            "answer2": "The shrine is to the east then north!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have the rune?",
            "yesanswer": "Now learn the mantra, and seek the green stone in 'Wrong'!",
            "noanswer": "Ask Talfourd for he knows of the rune."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 38,
        "x_pos1": 3,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Druid",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A wandering druid.",
            "job": "I seek justice.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "JUST",
            "keyword2": "SHRI",
            "answer1": "Learn at the shrine!",
            "answer2": "The shrine is to the east then north!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have the rune?",
            "yesanswer": "Now learn the mantra, and seek the green stone in 'Wrong'!",
            "noanswer": "Ask Talfourd for he knows of the rune."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 39,
        "x_pos1": 16,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Druid",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A wandering druid.",
            "job": "I seek justice.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "JUST",
            "keyword2": "SHRI",
            "answer1": "Learn at the shrine!",
            "answer2": "The shrine is to the east then north!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have the rune?",
            "yesanswer": "Now learn the mantra, and seek the green stone in 'Wrong'!",
            "noanswer": "Ask Talfourd for he knows of the rune."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 39,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Druid",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A wandering druid.",
            "job": "I seek justice.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "JUST",
            "keyword2": "SHRI",
            "answer1": "Learn at the shrine!",
            "answer2": "The shrine is to the east then north!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have the rune?",
            "yesanswer": "Now learn the mantra, and seek the green stone in 'Wrong'!",
            "noanswer": "Ask Talfourd for he knows of the rune."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 39,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Druid",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A wandering druid.",
            "job": "I seek justice.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "JUST",
            "keyword2": "SHRI",
            "answer1": "Learn at the shrine!",
            "answer2": "The shrine is to the east then north!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have the rune?",
            "yesanswer": "Now learn the mantra, and seek the green stone in 'Wrong'!",
            "noanswer": "Ask Talfourd for he knows of the rune."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 18,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A big guard",
            "job": "To preserve the peace and insure justice!",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "PEAC",
            "keyword2": "JUST",
            "answer1": "A good life is inspired by love and guided by truth!",
            "answer2": "Justice means not only to punish the bad but also to reward the good!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou always just?",
            "yesanswer": "Unlikely!",
            "noanswer": "Strive to be!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 11,
        "y_pos1": 14,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A big guard",
            "job": "To preserve the peace and insure justice!",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "PEAC",
            "keyword2": "JUST",
            "answer1": "A good life is inspired by love and guided by truth!",
            "answer2": "Justice means not only to punish the bad but also to reward the good!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou always just?",
            "yesanswer": "Unlikely!",
            "noanswer": "Strive to be!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Pinrod",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A thin man.",
            "job": "I take council.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "COUN",
            "keyword2": "JUST",
            "answer1": "On justice.",
            "answer2": "Justice is hardest to find at the point of a sword, the steel is an agent of justice, humanity the perpetrator!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Fight ye for justice?",
            "yesanswer": "Good, the druids chant the mantra!",
            "noanswer": "Cad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Pinrod",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A thin man.",
            "job": "I take council.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "COUN",
            "keyword2": "JUST",
            "answer1": "On justice.",
            "answer2": "Justice is hardest to find at the point of a sword, the steel is an agent of justice, humanity the perpetrator!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Fight ye for justice?",
            "yesanswer": "Good, the druids chant the mantra!",
            "noanswer": "Cad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 89,
        "x_pos1": 23,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Frida",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A withered form.",
            "job": "See my poor baby I beg for him.",
            "heal": "I am starving and sick.",
            "keyword1": "BABY",
            "keyword2": "JUST",
            "answer1": "Oh, no, my baby is dying!",
            "answer2": "Jaana may join thee!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou give me money so that I can get my baby healed?",
            "yesanswer": "Thou art kind and just!",
            "noanswer": "Evil wretch, curse thee!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 90,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Short Round",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A small child",
            "job": "I work for Jones.",
            "heal": "I am fine.",
            "keyword1": "JONE",
            "keyword2": "QUES",
            "answer1": "I think Indi's on a quest!",
            "answer2": "I'm not so sure, but it should be fun!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou having fun?",
            "yesanswer": "Write to Lord British and tell him!!!",
            "noanswer": "I am so sorry we all wish you would!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 44,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a ranger",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A sleek ranger.",
            "job": "I search for a home.",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "HOME",
            "keyword2": "RANG",
            "answer1": "On the range!",
            "answer2": "Where the deer and the antelope play.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Ever heard of such a place?",
            "yesanswer": "Seldom is heard a discouraging word!",
            "noanswer": "Ah, what'ya have to ruin it for!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 45,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 23,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a ranger",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A sleek ranger.",
            "job": "I search for a home.",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "HOME",
            "keyword2": "RANG",
            "answer1": "On the range!",
            "answer2": "Where the deer and the antelope play.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Ever heard of such a place?",
            "yesanswer": "Seldom is heard a discouraging word!",
            "noanswer": "Ah, what'ya have to ruin it for!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 96,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Vorpal",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A mean nasty ugly villain!",
            "job": "I eat people who bug me!",
            "heal": "Hungry!",
            "keyword1": "VILL",
            "keyword2": "PEOP",
            "answer1": "That's me alright!",
            "answer2": "Like thee!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou here to bug me?",
            "yesanswer": "Eat death, scum puppy!",
            "noanswer": "Well thou art!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 89,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a poor beggar.",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A poor beggar.",
            "job": "I have sinned.",
            "heal": "Well treated.",
            "keyword1": "SINE",
            "keyword2": "FELO",
            "answer1": "I have gotten chests in the townes and killed non-evil creatures.",
            "answer2": "He is a mean nasty ugly villain!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Should thou be in with the felon?",
            "yesanswer": "Thou art in the wrong cell.",
            "noanswer": "Good."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 89,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a poor beggar.",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A poor beggar.",
            "job": "I have sinned.",
            "heal": "Well treated.",
            "keyword1": "SINE",
            "keyword2": "FELO",
            "answer1": "I have gotten chests in the townes and killed non-evil creatures.",
            "answer2": "He is a mean nasty ugly villain!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Should thou be in with the felon?",
            "yesanswer": "Thou art in the wrong cell.",
            "noanswer": "Good."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 39,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Dwp",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise druid.",
            "job": "Welcome thee to Yew city of justice!",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "JUST",
            "keyword2": "YEW ",
            "answer1": "Love no one more than the truth, for justice seeks no favors. Temper thy justice with understanding.",
            "answer2": "Yes 'tis a fair city!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou like it?",
            "yesanswer": "Let it be as thine!",
            "noanswer": "A pity."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 38,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Silent",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A chanting druid",
            "job": "Beh... Beh...",
            "heal": "Beh... Beh...",
            "keyword1": "BEH.",
            "keyword2": "BEH ",
            "answer1": "Beh... Beh...",
            "answer2": "Beh... Beh...",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 38,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Silent",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A chanting druid",
            "job": "Beh... Beh...",
            "heal": "Beh... Beh...",
            "keyword1": "BEH.",
            "keyword2": "BEH ",
            "answer1": "Beh... Beh...",
            "answer2": "Beh... Beh...",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 75,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Flamis",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "A burning fire.",
            "job": "I hold the fabric of the true nature of justice.",
            "heal": "Bright.",
            "keyword1": "JUST",
            "keyword2": "FABR",
            "answer1": "The virtue of justice draws its nature from the principles of truth and love!",
            "answer2": "Of justice.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou always been just?",
            "yesanswer": "Unlikely.",
            "noanswer": "At least thou art honest."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 39,
        "x_pos1": 23,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Talfourd",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise judge.",
            "job": "I decide justice.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "JUST",
            "keyword2": "RUNE",
            "answer1": "Justice is truth in action!",
            "answer2": "It is hidden well!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Can thou honestly claim to be guilty of no crime ever?",
            "yesanswer": "Doubtful.",
            "noanswer": "Then do thy penance in a cell, and with the felon search ye well."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 39,
        "x_pos1": 30,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Calumny",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A solemn druid.",
            "job": "I make spells.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "SPEL",
            "keyword2": "MAND",
            "answer1": "I invented quickness!",
            "answer2": "Mandrake root is found only in the Fens of the Dead and in the Bloody Plains where the ground is always damp.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Can thou cast it?",
            "yesanswer": "It requires but one bloodmoss!",
            "noanswer": "Adept."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A big guard.",
            "job": "We guard the jail.",
            "heal": "Fit.",
            "keyword1": "MISD",
            "keyword2": "FELO",
            "answer1": "That'll be the left cell.",
            "answer2": "That'll be the right hand cell. careful in there!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou come to turn thyself in?",
            "yesanswer": "In which cell dost thou belong, felonies or misdemeanors.",
            "noanswer": "Just visiting, eh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 12,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A big guard.",
            "job": "We guard the jail.",
            "heal": "Fit.",
            "keyword1": "MISD",
            "keyword2": "FELO",
            "answer1": "That'll be the left cell.",
            "answer2": "That'll be the right hand cell. careful in there!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou come to turn thyself in?",
            "yesanswer": "In which cell dost thou belong, felonies or misdemeanors.",
            "noanswer": "Just visiting, eh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 14,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A tall guard",
            "job": "To guard the court.",
            "heal": "Yes.",
            "keyword1": "JUST",
            "keyword2": "COUR",
            "answer1": "A good life is inspired by love and guided by knowledge.",
            "answer2": "Within this chamber justice is served.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have business before the court?",
            "yesanswer": "Then enter.",
            "noanswer": "Then do not disturb the proceedings!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 14,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A tall guard",
            "job": "To guard the court.",
            "heal": "Yes.",
            "keyword1": "JUST",
            "keyword2": "COUR",
            "answer1": "A good life is inspired by love and guided by knowledge.",
            "answer2": "Within this chamber justice is served.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have business before the court?",
            "yesanswer": "Then enter.",
            "noanswer": "Then do not disturb the proceedings!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 39,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Jaana",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A quiet druid",
            "job": "I strive to understand justice.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "JUST",
            "keyword2": "UNDE",
            "answer1": "True justice satisfies all, false none.",
            "answer2": "Let justice be thy calling not thy excuse!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou just?",
            "yesanswer": "Many a grave has been unjustly filled in the name of justice.",
            "noanswer": "Alas."
        }
    }
]